# Cynthia Brito-Mena

# Software Engineer

347-385-6470 | cvnthia.britom@gmail.com | Bronx, NY | linkedin.com/in/cvnthiabritomena | github.com/cb2866

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineer specializing in JavaScript web development, with 6+ years of experience working in the non-profit space. With attention to detail, organizational skills, analytical approach, and communication capabilities can effectively work across teams to drive lasting impact and help organizations fulfill their missions.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Proficient:** Node, JavaScript, React / Redux, Git, Github, Express, Sequelize

Knowledgeable: HTML5, Bootstrap, MUI, CSS3, DOM, Test-Driven Development (Chai, Mocha, Jasmine), SQL,

Firebase, React Native, Webpack, Salesforce

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

### PocketNYC | Developer | November 2022 | Link to the project

PocketNYC is a Progressive Web App that provides information on free and low-cost resources and public events around New York City. Designed with a focus on user experience and accessibility, PocketNYC also includes a mapping and calendar feature and information on events and resources.

- Team project built utilizing React, Redux, Express, Node, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, Leaflet, and NYC OpenData
- Designed frontend components using Bootstrap and MUI to create an easy-to-navigate site with subtle references to NYC culture, including the subway system
- Developed personal calendar and 'favorites' features using Redux, RESTful API routes, and React Big Calendar, enabling users to add events and resources to their personal calendar and list of favorites
- Created dynamic user feeds for both guest and logged-in users to highlight new events aligned with their location and expressed interests

#### Punko Fop! | Developer | October 2022 | Link to the project

Punko Fop! is an online store where users can browse and purchase their favorite figurines (inspired by Funko Pop!)

- E-commerce site and team project built using React, Redux, Express, Node, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, and Stripe
- Implemented Redux and RESTful API routes to allow a user to access information on all products available, product details, make updates to their cart, and check out their items
- Designed all frontend components with Bootstrap and CSS to create a responsive and user-friendly site

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Recreation Coordinator | Win | NY**

Aug 2020-July 2022 / Sep 2016- Sep 2017

- Responsible for planning and implementation of educational, recreational, and culturally responsive programming for youth living in temporary housing
- Managed a team of six Recreation staff, across three locations, and developed best practices as a team to ensure consistency in our program offerings
- Assisted the Director of Youth Services with onboarding new members of the Recreation team on administrative and programmatic responsibilities
- Established strong relationships with youth participants and their parents, informing them of services available to
  them on-site and in the nearby community, including SYEP, sleepaway camp opportunities, and free programs in
  the city
- Created marketing and promotional materials to encourage youth enrollment in the Recreation program and increased participation in virtual workshops across multiple Win locations

#### College Volunteer Engagement Coordinator | Project Sunshine | New York, NY July 2019 - July 2020

- Drove the growth of the college volunteer network, opening 20 new volunteer chapters nationwide
- Developed an online fundraising challenge that mobilized volunteers at over 20 college campuses and raised nearly \$25,000 to support hospital programming
- Redesigned Project Sunshine's college volunteer training to simplify data reporting processes and make supply logistics accessible for college volunteers, thereby increasing the accuracy of program reporting

### **Development & Volunteer Engagement Manager | DreamWakers | New York, NY** Jan 2019 – July 2019

- Analyzed speaker and education survey data from the "flashchat" sessions with students, providing leadership with weekly reports identifying opportunities for engagement
- Developed and implemented a communication plan to engage with past and current volunteers through targeted volunteer opportunities, including chats exploring Black History Month, Social Justice, and Women in STEM
- Provided Spanish translations on all Hispanic Heritage Month "flashchats" in the Fall of 2018

# Volunteer & Events Coordinator | Win | New York, NY

Sep 2017 – Jan 2019

- Managed in-kind donations and worked closely with staff across 12 temporary housing and supportive housing facilities to ensure families received high-need items, including clothing and personal hygiene items
- Developed curriculum-based learning programs for volunteer groups to utilize when working with youth at Win shelters; efforts resulted in improved corporate group retention and increased access to STEM curriculum for youth

# **EDUCATION**

# **Fullstack Academy Web Development Bootcamp**

May 2022 – Dec 2022

Software Engineering Certificate

Full-time, Full Stack JavaScript Web Development Immersive

**Barnard College** 

May 2015

Bachelor of Arts in Urban Studies

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Languages: Fluent in Spanish